Okay, so now I'm
going to show you
how to make a
short process video. So
what is a short
process video? A short
process video is a
10 to 20 minute
video that just lays
out a specific quick
fire process to get
a specific result. All
right, so these for
my avatar are some
of the best performing
ever for view cells
and leads. In fact,
if you look at
the overall performance of
all of them I've
ever made, they absolutely
annihilate everything else. So
the pros of a
short process video are
they're very quick to
watch. So if your
viewers are time strapped
like mine are, you
can impress them fast.
They're very simple to
make. They're easy to
implement and they're really
good for emails and
sales. The cons are
short. Now, some of
your avatars might actually
like length and they
might like depth, which
these don't really give
a huge amount of.
So it's something to
test, not once, multiple
times, but you might
just find... sometimes your
viewers just want longer
stuff. So who should
make these? Well, I
would say beginners, white
belts, as I call
you, blue belt novices
and black belt pros.
Right, so what type
of viewers like these?
Viewer types who want
fast action, not just
ideas. Like they literally
want a step -by
-step system to follow.
Busy people who value
clarity and simplicity. Buyers
who already know the
problem and they're actively
looking for solutions. Best
used to present a
clear system or workflow.
So if you're doing
an editing workflow or
like a morning routine
or a funnel setup.
When teaching strategy or
execution, it doesn't require
deep theory. Or you
can cut all the
deep theory out and
still help them get
an amazing result. But
also when the transformation
is simple but valuable.
So some people think
they need to do
these long deep dives
to give value. And
let's say this deep
dive was on making
a cake. A short
process would really be,
I'm going to show
you how to get
just the sponge of
every cake amazingly fluffy.
Instead of, I'm going
to show you how
to go from the
beginning, buying all the
stuff, the recipe to
putting the icing on
the end. The secret
sauce to these, give
fast action steps. Give
just enough action so
it doesn't overwhelm them.
But something that inspires
them to try it.
Show proof that your
system works. Give real
examples. Mistakes, giving too
much information and overwhelming
viewers. Making it feel
hard or complex or
scary. No call to
action to your email.
Not making your information
feel new, easy, inspiring.
And the strategy that
we use for making
these is, we basically
will just give a
five to six step
system to get a
specific result. Now, if
it requires 10 steps,
but five of them
get 80 % of
the results, just give
those five. You also
want to try and
pitch a lead magnet
in it that is
tailored to the video
if you can. So
if step three is
you need to build
some sort of checklist
to keep on top
of your actions, give
them the checklist. If
that makes sense. So
we want the lead
magnet to relate very
heavily to the video
if we can. Unless
you have a lead
magnet that for your
failing as fast as
you can system, you
discovered no matter what
video you put on
it, it signups. Then
you can just promote
that. And then you
want to point future
videos back to this.
Once you know it
converts for emails and
sales. So this is
the makeup of our
short process. It's pretty
simple. We have the
intro, the emotion brick
and the logic. And
as you'll see, it's
not emotion, logic, emotion,
logic, emotion, logic. We
have one big emotional
bit here. And then
the rest can literally
just be step one
and talking people through
your steps or framework.
So that emotion bit
might be a visual
demo, a story or
a metaphor that shows
people the problem, teases
the result, helps them
understand it, why it
matters, why they need
it and why it's
going to solve the
problem they have. And
then you just give
them steps to get
that result. So titles
you can use it.
Look, don't be cute.
We don't need to
come up with anything
crazy. You just need
to make it clear
they're going to get
a result they care
about. So. These are
just 10 minutes. Don't
just go and use
them. You need to
use your patent bank.
But how to X,
how to X in
Y timeframe, how I
X step by step.
X was hard until
I did this. Copy
this X it'll Y.
Just fill in the
blank for your own
niche. Thumbnails. I'd recommend
sticking to the result,
the cognitive dissonance, the
comparison or curiosity. The
result, you just show
the result they want.
Cognitive dissonance, you challenge
what they thought to
be true. The statement
like don't buy a
house. Comparison you show
before and after. And
the curiosity, you just
find a way to
make them go. How?
What? Or why? And
that is what really
matters. Whoops. That's the
most bodged line of
all time. The intro,
the same as always.
We need a hook,
a problem, result, a
setup, some credibility plus
proof that you are
legit in there. And
you need to match
your viewers expectations. And
then in the emotion
brick, we've got some
options. So we can
tease the old way
that they're currently doing
doesn't work. And there
is a new way.
And this is often
what I do. We
then show them the
problem they have now.
And then show the
result that the new
way will get. That's
one way of doing
it. As an example,
which I often use.
And I'll link to
my videos so you
can see how I
do this in action.
The logic brick, you
then just list the
steps to get a
result. Only the most
critical ones. And if
at any point the
step is complex, use
an emotion brick to
simplify it first. So
we might get to
step four and go,
do you know what?
This one people always
mess up and don't
understand. I need to
show a visual demo.
I need to tell
a story because they're
not going to believe
this unless I can
prove it's true. So
you throw in an
emotion brick because you
know the step is
going to be challenging.
And you might only
need to do that
once. You might not
need to do it
at all. It's video
by video. And then
the end screen. If
you're optimizing for views,
push to previous versions
of this template if
they performed. Optimizing for
sales, push to a
higher converting video for
sales. Optimizing for email,
push to a high
converting video for email.
So here's an example
of my scripts in
action. And you can
see the intro. I've
color coded it. Hook,
problem result, setup transition.
I'll read a bit
of it, but then
I'll let you take
it over from there
and read it in
your own time. This
was called copy this
editing. The style, it
will blow up your
business. Will editing your
videos less make you
more money? I believe
the answer is yes.
That was my result.
So in this video,
I'm going to show
you the new way
to edit videos so
that they pass on
maximum value and impact
to your viewers whilst
growing your business in
return. And you'll like
it because it's so
much less work and
way easier to outsource
to. To start, you
need to understand how
big a shift in
editing I'm seeing in
the business space. So
you're not putting clients
off with outdated style.
See that? That's my
transition. And then we
go into the emotion
brick. I literally say.
Old way was this
stock footage, advanced animation,
tons of B roll,
lots of cuts, music,
sound effects, templates, zooms,
as much motion as
possible, basically adding stuff
to level up the
visual experience. But me
and my editor, Greg,
have been testing this
for 12 months now.
Credibility. And when we
cut it all out
and came out of
a new style, there
was an instant shift
in results. Credibility. I
got more comments, more
leads, more sales and
conversions. Credibility.
So it's all we're
going to do from
now on. That's it.
That's the old way
versus new way done.
This is the thing
you're doing. You're doing
wrong. I tried a
new way. It worked
better. And then the
transition is and step
one is simply loading
in your A roll
to the timeline. So
I have paid off
the entire point there,
which you might have
picked up on and
gone, hey, you told
us not to do
that. Well, look how
long the point is.
There is literally no
more information. I could
have just moved on
from there, but I
had to explain it
a bit because not
everyone knows what A
roll is. So I
said, this is just
you on camera talking.
You can just chop
out all the obvious
screw ups, pauses, stumbles.
That bit we had
an existential crisis. You
messed up for the
15th time. That's it.
And then step two,
we have the transition.
So we hook forward
to the value that's
coming. We'll stop your
viewers getting bored and
help you get more
consistent leads. It's very
powerful. So you see
the transition always sets
up. We've moved on
to the next bit.
And here's why it
matters. And then I
say, because it's going
to stop and go
and get to the
point that wrecks your
trust, which wrecks your
trust. So let me
show you exactly how
to fix that. There
was an example I
then play. So I'll
link to the video.
Right. And you can
see that my script
is a bit all
over the place. But
hopefully that was helpful
to a point. Right.
So now what we
go is to our
video planner. And if
you see down the
side, you are going
to have the short
process. These are the
videos I'm talking about.
What we can do
is you can go
check them out to
see how I've done
it. Just keep in
mind that I've been
building these templates. This
was the one I
was just reading. If
you want to check
it out and see
if you can spot
everything in action. Keep
in mind, I've been
building these templates and
refining them over time.
So they might not
always follow this exact
process, but this is
the one I've landed
on. So now what
we do is. Is
we set our goal.
Do you want sales,
emails or views? Just
pick one. You complete
your thumbnails and titles.
You then get your
viewers top three questions
so that we can
then plan to make
sure we match and
exceed their expectations. We
start off with a
messy brain dump. So
just list like 10
to 20 rough ideas
or insights or steps
you might want to
include. Doesn't have to
be 10 to 20.
Just as many as
you think are in
your head right now.
Don't worry about the
order. Just get the
information out your head.
You can also use
skyscraper bot to research
other videos on the
topic. To see. What.
The viewers loved and
the things they include.
Just get that down.
And then we refine
that messy plan into
the main points. So
for the emotion brick,
I've got a little
decision matrix here for
you. So basically if
you're struggling on working
out, like what's the
best way to get
emotion into this, you
can look at the
problem you've got and
say, is the problem
invisible or half of
yours to see? And
it will basically say,
yes, use a visual
demo, show the problem.
So this little decision
matrix is helpful. So
plan that. Then you
plan the logic brick
steps based on the
messy plan, which is
just step one, step
two, step. Three. If
at any point, one
of these steps was
a bit overly complex,
throw in an emotion
brick before it to
help simplify. And then
once we've got that
initial plan, we can
move on to writing
it, but try not
to go over eight
steps for this format.
It's going to be
short and then just
make sure for your
conversion strategy. If you're
optimizing for emails or
sales or views, you're
following this process and
making sure your calls
to action are in
early. You're doing obvious
or stealth selling, or
you're just not linking
to anything to get
views and then move
on to writing it,
then upload, add your
tracking. Links. And after
that, we come back
and we measure and
all we want to
know through measuring and
the system I teach,
which will learn in
the measurement section of
the program. Did you
hit your goal? Ask
why repeat the lesson
following my checklist. If
you missed your goal,
find out why following
my process, avoid the
lesson next time and
just remove the emotion.
All we got to
do is get data
into our pipeline peeps.
All right. Good luck.